Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
Well...
It really does look like the drawing, but...
Isn't she just the cutest thing?
That's definitely not it!
I know that!
We really don't have time for these jokes!
Really...
Where could she be?
The Führer's Son
East City!
You've arrived in East City!
Here's the latest news on Scar.
He's still on the run?
What a persistent guy.
Oh my, I'm terribly sorry.
No, it's my fault for not paying attention.
You are wearing some unusual attire.
Are you not from this country?
I'm from Xing.
Oh, my.
Are you here to see the sights?
There's not much to see in East City, is there?
No, I just stopped by because I need to switch trains here.
I'm headed to the North.
The train at Platform No. 3 is headed for North City.
Oh, no!
Thank you for helping me pick up the groceries!
If you are planning on riding with us, please board at once.
Have a safe trip!
Hm?
What a peculiar kitty.
Where did he go?!
I know I heard footsteps...
There he is!
So he was with a middle-aged man with black hair?
Yes. According to the reports, sir.
This is where he was yesterday.
So he's headed West, huh?
We have a few injured, some slightly, others seriously.
Scar must be desperate, too.
But even so...
...he's attracting a lot of attention.
Now, let's head off to work.
Well, whatever.
That has nothing to do with me.
A funeral, eh?
Yes, it seems so.
It isn't pretty, is it?
When you get old like me, you can't help but think about when you'll be the one getting buried.
What a terrible thing to say, madam.
As far as I can see, you have a long life ahead of you.
Lieutenant General Grumman?!
You said we were going to meet in front of Brigadier General Hughes' grave, right?
I figured it was something serious since you decided to take the measure of last resort.
To be doubly sure, I decided to disguise myself.
Well, I shouldn't have expected less from you, a man so famous for his eccentricity.
Your disguise exceeded my expectations.
Eccentric?
I'll take that as a compliment.
So, what's the matter?
Eastern Alchemy.
We may be able to find something in the Central Library.
Maybe.
Since we can't find the midget,
we'll have to search on our own.
I hope we can at least find some clues.
I see. So the entire upper echelon of Central is guilty, huh?
But you lost far too much in exchange for the information.
You have nothing left if they take away the men you can trust.
You're right, sir. I can't argue with that.
Even Raven, huh...
When I was in Central a little while ago, Raven asked me...
"Are you interested in a perfect, immortal army?"
Immortal army?
Was he talking about the Homunculi?
I flat-out rejected him, saying that it was rubbish.
Then soon after,
I was sent to Eastern Headquarters.
Relegated?
Thanks to that, I'm now stuck cleaning up after all the messes in the East.
More on that topic, do you happen to remember the riot in Lior?
The case where the Fullmetal Alchemist exposed the fake priest of Leto's conspiracy.
Yes, I do remember.
Although Lior was thrown into disarray,
the riot was quickly suppressed thanks to the
Eastern Army's rapid response while it was still minor.
But the Central Army intruded on the scene, and the Eastern Army was withdrawn.
Am I right?
Yes.
Lior's public order suddenly turned for
the worse when the Central Army entered the scene.
Those guys at Central are really
planning something, aren't they?
I don't even want to think about it!
Can't things be peaceful until I retire?
Again with the jokes.
You're the great Lieutenant General Grumman.
I'm sure you haven't felt satisfied for a second at simply being the head man for a region of the country.
You have the Eastern Army on your side;
full of veteran soldiers who experienced Ishbal.
I had always thought you'd use that secret contact memo when you needed to whine and beg me for help.
But you called me here to get me worked up, huh?
Geez...
Now that things are getting interesting in Central,
the flame of ambition in my heart has been lit once more.
Don't get too serious or your makeup will be ruined, madam.
Oh, no!
Are you free after this?
If you don't mind, would you like to join me for a cup of tea?
Oh, no, thank you.
I appreciate the invitation, but...
It's no good.
Why doesn't this place have any good books on Eastern Alchemy?
Maybe I'll just visit Xing and study there instead...
Wait, but there's no way I'll be able to cross that desert with my automail...
There you are, Edward Elric.
M-Major! What are you doing here?!
Shh!
You have to be quiet in the library.
I heard you're after a girl from Xing
who carries around a black and white cat.
Yeah.
Wait, how did you know that?
I heard from Colonel Mustang.
I'm here today on the Colonel's orders.
Apparently, she's headed north.
According to a witness, she was in
East City and was headed north from there.
North, huh?
Okay. If we know that much, it's safe to give it a try.
Thanks a lot, Major.
Tell the Colonel I said thanks, too.
Hang on.
Don't be in such a rush.
Take this with you.
What's this?
It's a letter of introduction.
It may not do you much good,
but you should meet her first.
Meet who?
She resides even farther north than the Northern Headquarters.
A general who guards the Drakma border and holds another name, the "Northern Wall of Briggs"...
...Major General Armstrong.
Hurry!
You've got nowhere to run, Scar!
Where did he go?!
Report this to Headquarters!
That train is headed for West City!
Damn him...
I can't really find much on Eastern Alchemy...
May's long-distance transmutation was awesome.
I wish I could use that...
I should have asked her about it when she was still at Dr. Nox's place.
Ling said that it's used predominantly for medical purposes...
Are you the Fullmetal Alchemist's little brother who wears a giant suit wherever he goes?
Y-Yes...
Amazing!
Wow! Wow!
Thanks...
But you need to keep it down. We're in a library.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What are you studying?
Eastern Alchemy.
Eastern Alchemy?
It's a form of alchemy used in Xing.
Wow... Xing, huh?
But aren't you Elric Brothers skilled enough to be state qualified in Amestris, a nation so advanced in alchemy?
Why are you researching minor forms of alchemy used in other countries?
Huh?
I can't exactly say, "I'm looking for a way to get my body back and fight Homunculi"...
Umm...
They say that Eastern Alchemy is used predominantly for medical purposes.
I'm researching to see if there are any other ways human lives could be saved.
Wow! Nothing less to be expected from the Elric Brothers!
Al! Alphonse!
Get your things together! We're leaving!
Brother, you have to keep it down in the library!
Wait, where are we going?
I'll explain the details on the way.
Either way, we need to go.
Go to the hotel and pack.
Whose brat is this?
If you're his brother, it must mean you're Edward, the State Alchemist!
Yeah.
Wow!
So the rumors were true! You really are a tiny alchemist!
What?!
H-Hey...
Say that again...
Come on, say it again.
You're up for a ride.
Want me to blast you to Neptune?
Wow!
So they were right! You get really angry when people say you're short!
Back away from Sir Selim!
You can't shoot him!
Don't tell me... you're Selim Bradley?
The Führer President's son?!
Yup! That's right!
What the heck are we doing here?
Aren't we supposed to be headed north?
Not like it was my choice...
I'm sorry.
This boy has admired you for so long, Mr. Edward.
Admired?
Do you like alchemy, Selim?
I do.
My dream is to learn alchemy and become a State Alchemist like Mr. Edward.
Admired me, huh...
Wow...
Then, I want to be useful to Father.
Do you love your Father...
...Führer President King Bradley?
Of course!
What's he like?
He's a very noble man.
He perseveres through hard work that would make a normal person cry...
...and works every day with only one thing in mind: the well-being of his people.
I see.
The Führer President does  seem busy all the time.
Yes, he is.
He still plans on working to his fullest in active service.
I'm constantly telling him to retire already, bearing his age in mind.
He's always been someone totally committed to his work.
He can do his job, but he's always been a blockhead when it comes to women.
He was so impolite; I gave him a good slap across the face.
Well, that's where it all started. Then, we started dating.
And our first date was...
Oh, my.
I didn't mean to talk about senseless things.
Father!
What a surprise!
Welcome home!
Thanks, Selim.
Why the surprise visit?
I had some rare free time, so I came to see your faces.
Then, I heard the Fullmetal Alchemist was here.
Hello.
It's been a while.
We just saw each other at Central Headquarters, didn't we?
I see. So you met each other at the library.
Yep!
What, are you trying to say that we don't look alike?
N-No, that's not it...
We're not connected by blood.
We were never able to have kids.
So we adopted him from a relative.
He grew up to become a kind boy who cares so much for his parents.
Stop it, Father.
It's embarrassing.
I'm only stating the truth.
Is something the matter?
N-No, it's just that we only see you when you're working at Headquarters.
So it's just... right, Brother?
I guess we're just stunned to see such a different side of you.
I see.
I, too, have family.
Even someone like me.
Although it's a bit different from your family.
Are you leaving already, Father?
Yeah. It's about time for me to return to the office.
Enjoy your stay,
State Alchemist.
Let's go.
Come visit again!
Okay, thanks.
I don't think his wife or son know that he's a Homunculus...
Anyway, we need to head north! All the way!
We need to get a hold of that midget and
make her tell us the secret behind Eastern Alchemy!
Right!
We'll be there by morning.
Sleep for now.
I see... so you let them get away again.
This is a map of the West, correct?
Yes, sir.
He was last seen...
Here.
And this is West City.
Scar and Marcoh disappeared somewhere in between.
A train must slow down significantly at a curve, correct?
Is it possible for someone to jump off?
I wouldn't say it's impossible, but it's very dangerous.
I see.
Well then, I wonder which direction they ran after they jumped off?
North...
...or south...
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
Could it be our first time traveling north?
Yeah.
I wonder if we'll be able to see snow?
Snow, huh...
I guess it rarely stuck to the ground in Resembool.
The cat and the mouse.
Insanity and hatred clash in a white world.
The fiercest battle yet opens the gate to a new world.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 33, The Northern Wall of Briggs.
The Northern Wall
of Briggs
Her golden hair is a flame made of ice.